American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIb. 1807-1825 APS.Archives.IIb APS.Archives.IIb
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Report of committee on the library, December 1, 1820; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [to the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau and three others. Concerning classification and location of books.
  - Report of committee on Judge Gibson's paper on geology in Pennsylvania, Dec. 1, 1820; 4x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Zaccheus Collins and R.M.Patterson. 1p.and end. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., II, 156 ff.
  - Report of committee on letter on meteorological observations in Missouri by T.G. Bower [Mower.), Dec. 1, 1820; 4x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M.Patterson, James Mease, and Wm. P.Dewees. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.497.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, librarian of A.P.S., Dec. 1, 1820; 6 1/2" x 8 1/4"; Collin, Nicholas, 1746-1831
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end Donations form the Swedish Royal academy of sciences sent by Jacob Berzelius. Transcribes extract from Berzelius's letter relative to investigation of the American languages and their comparison with others.
  - Testimonial from the American Philosophical Society for Joseph Correa de Serra, 1820 December 1; American Philosophical Society.
    Copy of a complimentary letter to the Chevalier Correa de Serra by the President and Vice President of the A.P.S..
  - Report on paper upon a varnish obtained from poplar buds, [Philadelphia], December 15, 1820; 8" x 9 3/4"; Collins, Zaccheus, 1764-1831. American Philosophical Society
    3 pp. and endorsements. D.S. Zaccheus Collins, William Hembel, jr. Report of committee upon paper submitted for Extra-Magellanic premium. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 498.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 19, 1820; 10x8; Rusconi, Mauro, 1776-1849
    London, A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p. and end. Forwards volumes.
  - Suggested prospectus for a publication of the James Logan correspondence, copied by Mrs. Deborah Norris Logan, [1820]; American Philosophical Society. Historical & Literary Committee.
    Prospectus for a publication of the James Logan correspondence. See also James Logan Letterbooks, 3 volumes and Table of Contents for the Correspondence [A.P.S. Archives].
  - Memorandum concerning purchases made through Mr. Hassler, 1820; 7x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    [ca. ?] A.D. 1p. Refers to Michaux.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, 1820; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Leeke, Charles
    A.L.S. 3P.and end. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 47.) Concerning his method propelling boats.
  - Letter to the secretary of the A.P.S., Jan. 5, 1821; 8" x 10"; Botta, Carlo, 1766-1837
    (?) A.L.S: Charles Botta. 1p. and end. In French. Presents a set of the third edition of his History of America [Storia della guerra dell'independenze...].
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 21, 1821; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. "Duplicate." 1p. and end. Forwards publications.from Rusconi.
  - W[illiam] Vaughan to John [Vaughan], January 21, 1821; 7 13/16" x 9 13/16"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S., in the name of Dr. Mauro Rusconi, two anatomical works.
  - Books bought by F.A. Michaux, 1821 Feb. 2; American Philosophical Society.
    List of books, dated Feb. 2, 1821, that were purchased by Francois Michaux for the American Philosophical Society for a sum o $3055.00.
  - Report of committee on Mr. Hentz's paper on crocodiles, Feb. 16, 1821; 3-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: James Mease and W.E.Horner. 1p.and end. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., II, 216 ff.
  - Report of the committee on F. R. Hassler's communication relative to the improvement of the navigation of rivers in mountainous countries, February 16, 1821; 7 5/8" x 9 7/16"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Adverse report.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 23, 1821; 10x8; Chazotte, Peter Stephen, ca. 1770-ca. 1849
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Sends pamphlet.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the paper of Mr. [F. R.] Hassler "upon a method of improving the navigation of rivers in mountainous countries,", March 2, 1821; 7 7/8" x 12 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] M. Patterson, William Strickland, James Mease. Publication not recommended.
  - Report of committee on Hassler's paper on navigation, March 2, 1821; 7-1/2x6; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.500.
  - Levett Harris to John Vaughan, March 9, 1821; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Levett
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his diploma of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., March 9, 1821; 12-1/2 x 8; Lesseps, Matthieu Maximilien Prosper, comte de, 1774-1832
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards books.
  - P[arker] Cleaveland to John Vaughan, March 23, 1821; 4 5/8" x 7 1/8"; Cleaveland, Parker, 1780-1858
    Brunswick, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns some journals (not named) to Mr. Vaughan.
  - Sam[uel] F. Jarvis to Robert Walsh, jr., March 31, 1821; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Jarvis, Samuel F. (Samuel Farmar), 1786-1851
    Corresponding Secretary of the A.P.S., Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 31, 1821; 10x8; Young, M.
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning shipments of government publications to the APS and to William Vaughan.
  - Daniel Brent to John Vaughan, April 2, 1821; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Brent, Daniel, 1774-1841
    Department of State, Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Returns books, listed herein, borrowed by the secretary of state [John Quincy Adams] "some time ago."
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, April 2, 1821; 10x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    London, L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, April 8, 1821; 10x8; Académie impériale et royale des sciences et belles-lettres (Belgium)
    Brussels, L.S.: Delle(?). 1p., end. In French. Forwards publication.
  - John Quincy Adams to John Vaughan, April 10, 1821; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Is returning the books he had borrowed. Desires a complete set of the A.P.S. Transactions for the Department of State.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, librarian of the Philosophical society, April 21, 1821; 5" x 8"; Harris, Levett
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Sends certain of the works of the late Count John Potocky (sic).
  - Letter of acknowledgment to John Heckewelder, 1821 April; American Philosophical Society.
    Acknowledgment form to John Heckewelder, thanking him for the donation of books to the A.P.S., signed by R. M. Patterson, Corresponding Secretary.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 1, 1821; 9-1/2x8; Niles, John M. (John Milton), 1787-1856
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p., end. and add. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., May 13, 1821; 10x8; Imperatorskai︠a︡ akademīi︠a︡ nauk i khudozhestv (Russia)
    [received] L.S.: Nicolas Fuss. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Lease issued to Athenaeum for rooms in Philosophical hall, May 17, 1821; 7 3/4" x 12 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    D.S: G. Ord, secy. 2p. and end. Seal
  - Jno. Pickering to Robert Walsh, jr., May 17, 1821; 8 3/8" x 9 13/16"; Pickering, John, 1777-1846
    Corresponding Secretary of the A.P.S., Salem, Mass., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his diploma of membership in the A.P.S. Encloses admission fee.
  - Note to Mr. Walsh to notify Clem C. Biddle, etc., of election to the Society, May 20, 1821; 5x6; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.D. 1p.and add.
  - Extract, May, 1821; Journal des savants
    D. 3p. In French. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 3, pp. 38-40.) Eulogy on Volney.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, May, 1821; 10x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L. filled in in ms. S.: Erman. 1p. and add., end. In Latin. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 21, 1821; 10x7-1/2; Turpin, P. J. F. (Pierre Jean François), 1775-1840
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p., end. and add. In French. Forwards publication.
  - W[illiam] Vaughan to John Vaughan, July 9, 1821; 7 5/8" x 9 11/16"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Secretary of the A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Transmits to the A.P.S.: Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society for 1820 and 1821.
  - Letter to A.O.H.Oelriche (?), Mannheim, July 13, 1821; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Resumé of A.L. 1p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 2, p.42.) Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 16, 1821; 10x8; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Regrets they cannot meet this evening. Concerning two Nanticoke vocabularies "in your possession."
  - Jno. Cleves Symmes to the President of A.P.S., July 18, 1821; 7 7/8" x 12 7/8"; Symmes, John Cleves, 1780-1829
    Newport, Ky., 1 p., address and endorsement. Requests that A.P.S. publicly "declare their opinion, relative to my new Planetary Theory;.. ."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 21, 1821; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, A.L.S.: Josiah Quincy, cor. sec. 1p. and add., end. Sends Pt.2 of Vol. 4 of their Memoirs.
  - Isaiah Thomas to J[ohn] Vaughan, July 24, 1821; 7 3/4" x 9 1/8"; Thomas, Isaiah, 1749-1831
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Worcester, Mass., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for forwarding the Laws of Louisians to the American Antiquarian Society.
  - W(illia)m Tilghman, J(oh)n Vaughan, and N(athaniel) Chapman to Anne Patterson, July 26, 1821; 8" x 10"; Chapman, Nathaniel, 1780-1853
    Philadelphia,1 p. and endorsement. L. Copy. Letter of condolence to Mrs. Patterson upon the death of her husband.
  - W(illia)m Tilghman, J(oh)n Vaughan, July 26, 1821; 8" x 10"; Tilghman, William
    and N(athaniel) Chapman to Anne Patterson, Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. L. Copy. Letter of condolence to Mrs. Patterson upon the death of her husband.
  - W(illia)m Tilghman, July 26, 1821; 8" x 10"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    J(oh)n Vaughan, and N(athaniel) Chapman to Anne patterson, Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. L. Copy. Letter of condolence to Mrs. Patterson upon the death of her husband.
  - Letter to Wil[helm] von Humboldt, July 28, 1821; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L. 3p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 2, pp.44-46.) Forwards publications. Refers to Indian languages.
  - Letter to the president and secretary of the Philosophical society, July 30, 1821; 8" x 9 3/4"; Say, Jean Baptiste, 1767-1832
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French Donations.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Philadelphia, July 31, 1821; 9-1/2x7-1/2, 19-1/2x16-1/2; Lambert, William
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Enc.of 2p., end. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Math.and astronomy, vol. 2, no. 101.) Encloses tables of the moon's transit over the meridian of Washington.
  - D[aniel] Raymond to [John] Vaughan, Secretary of the A.P.S., September 4, 1821; 8" x 9 3/4"; Raymond, Daniel, 1786-1849
    Baltimore, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: his work on political economy and three pamphlets.
  - James P. Wilson to Peter S. DuPonceau, September 16, 1821; 7 7/8" x 9 3/8"; Wilson, James P.
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a copy of the last will and testament of the late Emperor of China.
  - Letter to [Johann Severin] Vater, Sept. 21, 1821; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Resumé of A.L. 1p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol.2,p.59.) Concerning Indian languages.
  - Letter to William Tudor, Sept. 21, 1821; 8x5; Gardiner, Emma Jane Tudor
    [presented,] A.L. 2p. and add.,end. Forwards publication.
  - James Workman to Robert Walsh, jr., September 22, 1821; 8" x 9 5/8"; Workman, James, d. 1832
    New Orleans, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to R. M. Patterson, Sept. 26, 1821; 9x7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
  - Report of committee on the memoirs of E.P. James, Oct. 5, 1821; 4x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M.Patterson and Thos. Nuttall. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.504. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., II, 172 ff.
  - Letter to [John Gottlieb Ernestus Heckewelder], Oct. 8, 1821; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    L. 2p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks. vol. 2, pp.60-61.) Concerning Indian linguistics. Printed in part: Mass.Hist.Soc.Collections, Ser.2,vol.9, xxxiv-xxxv.
  - Letter to [Friedrich von] Adelung, St. Petersburg, Oct. 13, 1821; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, L.S. 2p. In French. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 3 pp.1-2.) Concerning Indian language publications. Friendly letter.
  - Geometric exemplification of temperature, wind and weather for 1820 at Washington, Oct. 19, 1821; Meigs, Josiah, 1757-1822
    [presented] D. 1p.,end. Cf. Minutes, p.505.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Nov. 19, 1821; 7 1/4" x 9 1/4"; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, L.S: H[orace] H[ayman] Wilson, secretary. 1p.and add.,end. Acknowledges letter of April 12, Vol.1, n.s. of A.P.S. Transactions, a volume of Historical Transactions in the history department of the American Society and Heckewelder's Nar-rative of the Moravian Mission to the Indians from 1740-1808.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Nov. 23, 1821; 10x8; Deabbate, Gaspard
    Philadelphia, L.S. 4p.and end. In French. Returns the Turin academy's thanks for publication and lists its holdings of the APS publications.
  - Letter to Robert Walsh, Philadelphia, Nov. 29, 1821; 10x7-1/2; Università di Pisa
    Pisa, L.S.: Joseph Piazzini. 2p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 30, 1821; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schaeffer, F. C. (Frederick Christian), 1792-1831
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Encloses pamphlet for the A.P.S. Desires to borrow Ebeling's History of New York from the library; contemplates translating this work.
  - Report of committee on a form for meteorological tables by Meigs, Dec. 14, 1821; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Mathew Carey, R.Patterson and Zaccheus Collins. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.506.
  - W(illia)m Meade to the President of the A.P.S., December 14, 1821; 8" x 9 3/4"; Meade, William
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests permission to deposit his collection of minerals with the A.P.S. Refused.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 20, 1821; 8x5; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p., end. and add. Forwards publications.
  - Report of committee on Dr. Meade's request for room in Philosophical Hall, Dec. 21, 1821; 7-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M.Patterson, Zaccheus Collins and G.Ord. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.507.
  - R[edmond] Conyngham to Peter S. DuPonceau, December 27, 1821; 7 13/16" x 9 13/16"; Conyngham, Redmond, 1781-1846
    Conyngham, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: copies of historical documents relative to the Wyoming controversy.
  - Letter to R[obert] Patterson, President of A.P.S., December 27, 1821; 7 1/2" x 8 3/4"; Wetterstedt, Gustavus, comte de, -1837
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 3p. and end. In French. Acknowledges election to membership.
  - M[ahlon] Dickerson to John Vaughan, December 29, 1821; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Dickerson, Mahlon, 1770-1853
    Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Thinks the philosophical and historical societies should have been included in the resolution for distributing documents. Concerning customs regulations.
  - Report of the committee on appointed to consider the expediency of petitioning Congress for the abolition of the duty on the importation of books, January 4, 1822; 7 13/16" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau, R[obert] M. Patterson. Report draught of petition for adoption.
  - Report of the committee appointed to consider the expediency of petitioning Congress for the abolition of the duty on the importation of books, January 4, 1822; 8 1/2" x 13 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 4 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Peter S. DuPonoeau, R[obert] M. Patterson. Comparison of import duties in various countries.
  - John Sergeant to Robert Patterson, January 16, 1822; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Sergeant, John, 1747-1824
    President of the A.P.S., Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of memorial from the A.P.S., which has been presented and referred to the committee of ways and means.
  - Samuel Humphreys to W. P. C. Barton, January 17, 1822; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Humphreys, Samuel, 1778-1846
    Southwark, 1p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses information (missing) about a ship's masts.
  - Letter to the President and Secretary of the American philosophical society, Jan. 20, 1822; 9-1/2x8; Say, Jean Baptiste, 1767-1832
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and end. In French. Presents publication to the APS. Refers to his donation of 4th edition of his treatise on political economy.
  - Lardner Vanuxem to George Ord, January 20, 1822; 7 3/4" x 9 13/16"; Vanuxem, Lardner, 1792-1848
    Secretary to the A.P.S., Columbia, S. C., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Report of Committee appointed to consider accommodations in Philosophical Hall for the Athenaeum, Jan. 26, 1822; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Phila., D.S.: R. Patterson, Benjn. R. Morgan. J.E. Hall. 2p. and end. Involves quarters used by Mr. Sully.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 26, 1822; 7 1/4" x 9"; Poletika, Petr Ivanovich, 1778-1849
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Acknowledges election to membership in A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Feb. 5, 1822; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    London, L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p. and end. Forwards publication.
  - W[illiam] Tudor to John Vaughan, February 13, 1822; 7 11/16" x 9 1/2"; Tudor, William, 1779-1830
    Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards two copies of a report made to the Massachusetts legislature regarding penal laws and penitentiary systems.
  - P. Pedersen to J[ohn] Vaughan, February 19, 1822; 4 15/16" x 7 3/4"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. Transmits to the A.P.S., the Transactions of the Royal Danish Academy of Sciences at Copenhagen.
  - B. Stover to Thomas M. Euen, February 22, 1822; 7 7/8" x 10"; Stover, B.
    Cincinnati, Ohio, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a collection of political and historical tracts printed in the reign of Queen Anne.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the paper submitted by Mr. Samuel Humphreys on a new principle of placing masts in ships, March 1, 1822; 7 7/8" x 12 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 5 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: W[illiam] Jones, R[obert] M. Patterson, G[eorge] Ord. Adverse report.
  - N(icholas) Collin to Rob(ert) Patterson, March 1, 1822; 6 1/8" x 7 5/8"; Collin, Nicholas, 1746-1831
    President of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Proposes Joens Svanberg and Zacharias Nordmark for membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Robert Walsh, jr., corresponding secretary of A.P.S., March 9, 1822; 7 1/2" x 9"; Poletika, Petr Ivanovich, 1778-1849
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Acknowledges election to membership in the Society.
  - Report of the Committee on the Library, in re preparation of a complete catalogue., 1822 March 14; American Philosophical Society.
    Resolution of the Library Committee that a Complete Catalog be created of "all of the Books, Pamphlets & Manuscripts belonging to the Society." Also, it was resolved that a sum of $50.00 be allocated for the purpose.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., March 25, 1822; 9-1/2x8; Societas Regia Scientiarum Upsaliensis
    Upsala, L.S.: Pehr. Fab. Aurivillius. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Papers pertaining to printing expenses, 1824 March 26- 1847 July 20; American Philosophical Society.
    Papers and receipts related to A.P.S. printing expenses.
  - L. H. Girardin to R[obert] Patterson, April 13, 1822; 7 7/8" x 9 11/16"; Girardin, Louis Hue, 1771-1825
    President of the A.P.S., Baltimore, 2 pp., address and endorsement A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his certificate of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Report of committee on Baron Larrey's pamphlet on yellow fever, April 19, 1822; 7-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: James Mease and Wm. P.Dewees. 1p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p.511.
  - Report of committee on C.W.Peale's occupancy of rooms, May 3, 1822; 8x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Jn.Vaughan, R.Patterson and James Mease. 1p. Cf. Minutes, p.511.
  - Letter to Robert Walsh, Philadelphia, May 3, 1822; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Haüy, René Just, 1743-1822
    Paris, L. "Copy" 2p. and add.,end.: D.B. Warden. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Report of the committee appointed to inquire into the expediency of renting the unoccupied apartments in the hall belonging to the Society, May 14, 1822; 8 1/8" x 13 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. D.S.: Adam Seybert, James Mease, Franklin. Bache.
  - (John) Vaughan to Committee of A.P.S., May 15, 1822; 7 3/4" x 8"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    L-2 Philadelphia, 1 p. D. Unsigned. Mr. Vaughan "is willing to become the tenant of the Society for all those parts of the Building which Mr. Sully leased of the Society, exclusive of the first floor,..."
  - Letter to R. M. Patterson, May 24, 1822; 9x7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
    London, L.S.: Joseph Sabine. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to D.B.Warden, May, 1822; 7x4-1/2; Vuillemot, Mme. Hauÿ
    [ca.]. L. "Copy" 1p. and add. and end. In French. Concerning Haüy's publication.
  - J. F. W. Herschel to the Secretary of the A.P.S., June, 1822; 7 3/8" x 9 1/16"; Herschel, John F. W. (John Frederick William), Sir, 1792-1871
    [London, ?] 2 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: [Royal] Astronomical Society, Transactions, I.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Beasley, Elizabethtown, N.J., July 5, 1822; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed D. filled in in ms.S.: J.Q. Adams. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications for use by the University of Pennsylvania.
  - Report of committee on Dr. Horner's article on muscles, July 19, 1822; 7-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: James Mease and Richd. Harlan. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.513.
  - Presentation note to the American philosophical society, July 19, 1822; 10x8; Netherlands. Ministerie van Binnenlandse Zaken en Landbouw
    N. 1p.and end. In French.
  - A list of books presented by A[dam] Seybert to the American Philosophical Society, August 16, 1822; 8 1/8" x 12 3/4"; Seybert, Adam, 1773-1825
    [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsements. D.
  - M. A. P. S. to [John] Vaughan, August 20, 1822; 6 5/8" x 8 1/16"; Anonymous